For the demo, let's log into our Google Cloud console.
Here, I'm inside the Google Cloud console.
I'm logged in as an organizational admin,
which gives me the permission to create the folders and
projects at the organizational level.
You can access this by navigating here.
Go to the IAM and admin and click on Manage resources.
This page is the tree view of your entire cloud footprint.
If your organization is brand new, you probably see only one thing,
your organization name, with generally your company name.
That's perfect.
But in my case,
I've already created a couple of projects and folders inside this organization.
That's why you are seeing a couple of them.
Let me just create one new folder.
So on the top here you see Create folder.
Let me create a folder, name as production and say Create.
Whenever you create the folder, internally,
Google assigns it a numeric ID corresponding to it.
For example, right now we are not able to see the folder that we have created.
Just click on Refresh so that it will be visible here.
Now you can see that I have a production folder, and I
can see a corresponding numerical ID.
We can think about creating multiple folders corresponding to environment.
For example, I can create one more folder for staging.
And similarly, I create one more folder for the development,
so I click on here, say Folder, and say development.
Now if I refresh it again,
I can see all those folder that I've already created, development,
staging, and production.
Now it's time to go ahead and populate these folders with application projects.
You might have multiple applications, maybe like payment service,
inventory service, or a notification service.
What you can think about is having all those
applications in each of these environments.
For example, let's click on Create project, and let's say create a project,
say, payment‑app‑service‑prod.
Now what I will do is I click on Browse here because I want this
project to get created within my development folder.
So I select the development and say Create.
Now you will see that under the Notifications, a project has started initiating.
Now,
if I simply refresh and if I expand this development
tab, you can see a project inside it.
Now what I can do is, when I move to the staging or I move to the production,
similarly,
I will create this kind of project into my staging
folder and in my production folder.
Maybe I have multiple applications.
So correspondingly, I can create multiple projects
within a single folder itself.
So if you look at it,
we have created the entire hierarchy for our
project, which involves development, staging,
and the production. And we have not talked about the IAM yet,
but the moment you create a folder,
a couple of roles have been assigned to these folders.
You can go down to the settings, and you can click on the IAM here
and you can see that, a couple of roles and permissions have been
assigned to this specific folder.